<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="Nexus File Navigator in Package Explorer">
  <intro>
    <description>
      This cheat sheet describes how to use the Nexus file navigation feature of the package explorer.
    </description>
  </intro>
  <item
        title="Open the folder containing the .nxs/.hdf5/.h5 files">
     <description>
        Once the Data Project is loaded, open the folder containing the Nexus files within the Project Explorer.
     </description>
  </item>

   <item
        title="Browsing the data through the Nexus Data Editor and the Package Explorer">
     <description>
        All Nexus/HDF5 files appearing in the project explorer can be opened as folders and once opened will display the list of their content.<br/><br/>
        Furthermore, by default, all resource files in the Project Explorer have decorators displaying the size, date of creation and title/scan command if present.
     </description>
  </item>
  <item
        title="Activate / deactivate the scan command and/or Nexus element decorator">
     <description>
        The scan command and Nexus sub element decorator (active by default) can be activated/deactivated through &apos;Window -> Preferences -> General -> Appearance -> Label Decorations&apos; or through the link below.<br/><br/>
        The label decorator that manages the scan command decoration is called &apos;Nexus Scan Command and Title Decorator&apos; for Nexus/HDF5 files and &apos;HF5 Tree Elements Decorator&apos; for the sub element of these files.<br/><br/>
     </description>
     <command
           required="false"
           serialization="org.eclipse.ui.window.preferences(preferencePageId=org.eclipse.ui.preferencePages.Decorators)"/>
  </item>
  <item
        title="Open the Nexus file in Nexus Data Editor">
     <description>
        In order to be able to display the Nexus file data in the DExplore plotting, we need to open the Nexus file with the Nexus Data Editor.<br/><br/>
        This can be done with &apos;Right Click on the Nexus file -> Open With -> Nexus Data Editor&apos;.<br/><br/>
        <b>Note</b>: the Nexus files can also be opened by double clicking on one of the Nexus file sub element, however the editor used to open the file will be the last one in the workspace history used to open the file.
     </description>
  </item>
  <item
        title="Navigate through the Nexus file data and have the plotting refreshed accordingly">
     <description>
        With the Nexus file opened in a Nexus Data Editor, select one of the Nexus file sub element in the Package Explorer.<br/><br/>
        Check that the plotting is updated accordingly.<br/><br/>
        <b>Note</b>: The HDF5 Editor will not be updated (no selection change) when a Nexus file sub-element is selected in the Package Explorer. Unlike for the DAT files discussed previously where the update works for both the editor and the plotting.
     </description>
  </item>
</cheatsheet>

