<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creating .info file">

	<intro>
		<description>
		    To load in a series of images, a text file which describes the layout of the images in the 3D space must be loaded.    
		    Render 3D uses .info files for this purpose. This is an example of a .info file which describes a volume which composes of five images:
		  	
		    <br />		    
		    # Amira Stacked Slices <br />
			pixelsize 1 1 <br /> 			
			volume00.tif 0 <br />
			volume01.tif 1 <br />
			volume02.tif 2 <br />
			volume03.tif 3 <br />
			volume04.tif 4 <br />
			<br />
			
			For more detailed information about this file format visit: http://walnut.zib.de/documentation/521/amira/usersguide/tutimageio.html
				    
      </description>
 	</intro>
	
 	   
   <item title="Generating .info file">
 	  <description>
		When the Render 3D view is opened by right clicking an iFolder and selecting the Render 3D option, the Render 3D plugin will search for a .info file in the directory of the selected iFolder.
		<br /> If no .info file is found, the display for creating a new .info will be shown. There are two ways to generate this file; by searching a folder for all of the image files, or by inputing the base name of the images along with the total number of images.
		<br /> The next two sections will describe these two approaches.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Generating by searching a folder">
 	  <description>
 	  	Using this option the produced .info file will consist of files found within the specified folder, <b>Folder to search</b>, that match the <b>Prefix</b> and <b>Image extension</b>.
 	  	<br />If both of these fields are left blank, all files in the specified folder will be added to the .info file.
 	  	<br />If only the <b>Image extension</b> is used all files with this extension will be used, this can be useful if you want to use all of the images in the folder, e.g. all ".tif" files.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Generating by using base name">
 	  <description>
 		Using this option will assume at all the images files you desire to use are named in the format: PREFIXxxxxx.EXTENSION where xxxxx starts at 00000 for the first image in the stack with a z position of 0, and that xxxxx increments by 1 to the next image.
 		<br />In the <b>Image extension</b> field the extension without the dot "." should be used. E.g. using ".tif" will produce items of the format PREFIXxxxxx..tif
      </description>           
   </item>
   
   
   <item title="Pixel size">
 	  <description>
 		The fields <b>Pixel size x</b>, <b>Pixel size y</b>, <b>Pixel size z</b> describe the mapping of the image pixels to the 3D volume.
 		<br /><b>Pixel size x</b> specifies for every pixel in the image along the x axis, how many pixels this represents in the 3D volume, likewise for <b>Pixel size y</b> and <b>Pixel size z</b>.
 		<br />The most common value for these fields is 1.
      </description>           
   </item>
 
   
   

</cheatsheet>
