<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Render 3D">

	<intro>
		<description>
		 Render 3D is used to produce images and videos of volumetric data using Avizo. Rotations and orthogonal slices of data can be produced.
		 <br />The processing can be done locally, and the tasks can also be send to the SGE cluster for remote processing. 
		 <br />Different displays can be opened by clicking their corresponding icon in the top right of the view. 
		 <br />The different rendering options are <b>Avizo Rotation Animation</b>, <b>Avizo Slice Snapshot</b>, <b>Avizo Slice Snimation</b>, <b>Avizo Rotation Snapshot</b>, <b>ImageJ Rotation Snapshot</b>.
		 <br />The file types which are supported are the same as which Avizo supports.
      </description>
 	</intro>
	
	
	<item title="Starting Render 3D">
 	  <description>
		Render 3D can be started two ways.
		<br />By opening the view; <b>Window -> Show View -> Other... -> Data Analysis -> Render 3D</b>   
		<br />By right clicking on a an iFolder and selecting <b>Render 3D Images</b>. 
      </description>
   </item>
 	   
   <item title="Rendering performance">
 	  <description>
		The rendering quality of data can in some cases be improved by checking the <b>Use Xvfb</b> option. This sends the display window to a X virtual frame buffer.
		<br />When using <b>Avizo Slice Snapshot</b> and <b>Avizo Rotation Snapshot</b>, a slight difference can be noticed when the <b>Use Xvfb</b> option is enabled.
		<br />When using <b>Avizo Rotation Animation</b> a considerable difference can be noticed when the <b>Use Xvfb</b> option is enabled. 
		Producing 3D rotation images with <b>Avizo Rotation Animation</b> and the <b>Use Xvfb</b> option enabled produces images in much higher detail than <b>Avizo Rotation Snapshot</b>.
		<b>Avizo Slice Animation</b> uses Xvfb by default and this can not be disabled, as it is required to function correctly.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Avizo Rotation Animation">
 	  <description>
 	  	<b>Camera rotation x</b>, <b>Camera rotation y</b>, <b>Camera rotation z</b> define the position of the camera facing the object. The rotation of the camera is with regard to the center of the object.
 	  	<br />Rotating the camera allows the object to be seen at different angles, as the rotation of the object can only be done on one axis. 
 	  	<br />The <b>Compression quality</b> specifies the quality of the movie produced. Where 1 is the highest quality and 0 is the lowest quality.
      </description>
   </item>
   
    
 
   
   

</cheatsheet>
