<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Compare Files Editor Introduction">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This tutorial will show you how to use the compare files editor.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Introduction">
		<description>
			The purpose of the compare files editor is to enable the user selection of a dataset in
			one file and compare that with the corresponding datasets in other files using the
			dataset inspector. There are two parts to a compare files editor: the top part is a
			table of the files selected earlier and the bottom part is a sub-editor opened at first
			file.
			<br/><br/>
			The files table comprises three columns. The left column contains a check entry in each
			row that indicates if the file should be used (if possible). Clicking on the entry will
			toggle its usage state. When the check is not visible, the file will not be used. The
			entry will also indicate with a <b>yellow</b> background if the file does not contains
			the chosen dataset (when one has been chosen). The centre column shows the full file
			name for the row. The right column is titled Value and starts by at zero for the first
			file - it represents a per-file value.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Choosing a dataset">
		<description>
			You can choose a dataset in sub-editor in the same way as for a single file. Single or
			double clicking a dataset will make the compare files editor search through its list of
			files and search for a dataset of the same name. If no dataset is found in a file, a
			yellow warning is shown. All datasets are aggregated together into a single dataset,
			possible axes and the per-file values are sent to the dataset inspector. 
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Choosing a metadata item for per-file values">
		<description>
			Right-clicking in the sub-editor can allow you to select per-file values from a file's
			data or metadata items. The last column in the file table will show the selected
			per-file values. In this case, the column heading switches to show that item's name and
			any missing values are highlighted with a yellow background. A right-click on the column
			title brings up a menu item to reset the values to row indices.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Adding more files">
		<description>
			The table supports the insertion of more files by the action of dragging from any source
			of files and dropping them anywhere below the first row.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
