<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compositeCheatsheet name="DExplore Introduction">
	<taskGroup name="DExplore Introduction">
		<intro>
			This introduction will show you how to use some basic features of the data exploration,
			<b>DExplore</b>, perspective.
		</intro>
		<onCompletion>
			Congratulations, you have completed the tutorial and now know how to use the data
			exploration perspective.
		</onCompletion>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Open Data Exploration Perspective">
			<param name="path" value="OpenDExplore.xml"/>
			<param name="showIntro" value="false"/>
			<intro>
			</intro>
		</task>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Accessing Your Data" skip="true">
			<param name="id" value="uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.analysis.rcp.contributions.FileOpenCheatSheet"/>
			<intro>
				Access to your data can be achieved in a variety of methods. This tutorial explains
				those methods.
			</intro>
			<onCompletion>
				Congratulations, you have successfully open a data file in the editor area.
			</onCompletion>
		</task>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Understanding the File Editors" skip="true">
			<param name="id" value="uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.analysis.rcp.contributions.FileEditorCheatSheet"/>
			<intro>
				The data file is presented in the editor area in different manners according to
				their format type. This tutorial explains those types.
			</intro>
			<onCompletion>
				Now, select an item to inspect and read the next tutorial.
			</onCompletion>
		</task>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Inspecting Your Data" skip="true">
			<param name="id" value="uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.analysis.rcp.contributions.InspectorCheatSheet"/>
			<intro>
				After selecting an item to inspect, choose how to examine or visualize it with the
				<b>Dataset Inspector</b>.
			</intro>
			<onCompletion>
				Congratulations, you have visualized your data. Play around further to familiarise
				yourself with the controls that manipulate the data. Understand the nature of
				multi-dimensional datasets.
			</onCompletion>
		</task>
	</taskGroup>
	<taskGroup name="DExplore Advanced Use">
		<intro>
			This tutorial will show you how to use advanced features of the data exploration,
			<b>DExplore</b>, perspective.
		</intro>
		<onCompletion>
			Congratulations, you have completed the tutorial and now know how to expertly use the
			data exploration perspective.
		</onCompletion>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Accessing Multiple Files In Your Data" skip="true">
			<param name="id" value="uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.analysis.rcp.contributions.MultipleFileOpenCheatSheet"/>
			<intro>
				This tutorial explains how to open multiple files to compare equivalent datasets.
			</intro>
			<onCompletion>
				Congratulations, you have successfully open a set of files in the editor area.
			</onCompletion>
		</task>
		<task kind="cheatsheet" name="Comparing Multiple Files" skip="true">
			<param name="id" value="uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.analysis.rcp.contributions.CompareFilesCheatSheet"/>
			<intro>
				In the previous step, you opened a set of files for comparison. This tutorial
				explains how to use the compare files editor.
			</intro>
			<onCompletion>
				Congratulations, you have compared datasets from multiple files.
			</onCompletion>
		</task>
	</taskGroup>
</compositeCheatsheet>
