<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="DIVA - Looking at diffraction images">
   	<intro>
      	<description>
        	This Tutorial will show you how to get a first look at diffraction images to asses their general quality
    	</description>
   	</intro>
   	<item title="Open DIVA Perspective">
   		<command required="true"
   			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.diffractionviewerperspective)"/>
   		<description>	
   			The DIVA perspective is designed to make looking at diffraction images as easy as possible.
   		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open a Diffraction Image">
   	   	<description>
   			Use the Project Explorer, open the <b>data</b> project and the <b>examples</b> folder within it.
   			<br/><br/>Then select the first .img image. You will see the Metadata information appear in the Metadata view just below the navigator.
        	<br/><br/>Now double click on the selected .img file and you will see the image appear in the <b>MX image</b> editor in the middle of the window.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Navigating around the image">
   	   	<description>	
   	   		Move the mouse over to the <b>MX image</b> editor which shows the diffraction image and experiment with the following tools which are available to allow you to look around the image.
			<br/><br/><b>Scroll Wheel</b>
			<br/>Zoom in and out of the image
   	   		<br/><br/><b>The Panning tool</b>
			<br/>This is the tool selected by default, so just click on the image and drag it around to pan.
			<br/><br/>Finally to get information about where you are pointing at specifically, activate the <b>Pixel information</b> tool which can be found in the toolbar directly above the image -- it's in the Image tools drop-down and the tool-tip reads 'Image tools used to profile and inspect images'.
			<br/><br/>With this turned on, information can be found out about the image by moving the mouse pointer over it. The information is displayed in a new view that opens up.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Changing the colour scale on the image">
   	   	<description>	
			Sometimes to get the best out of the data, changing the way the pixel values are mapped to a specific colour can really help.
			<br/><br/>There is lots of functionality available here, but the easiest way to see a variety of different mappings is to use the <b>Colour mapping</b> tool in the <b>Image tools</b> drop-down. Select a different colour scheme, Try a few different ones, but then end up on 'Sqrt scale' which can be useful for pulling data out of the lower regions on the image.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Resolution Rings">
   	   	<description>	
			To see resolution rings on the image, use the tools in the <b>Resolution rings</b> drop-down. This allows various markers to be set on the image, including standards and ice rings.
			<br/><br/>First, select the <b>Beam Centre</b> tool, which will show a point on the image which is where the metadata puts the beam centre.
			<br/><br/>Now click on <b>Standard rings</b> to get a set of resolution rings, the values of which are displayed as labels on the rings. 
        </description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet> 
