<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="DIVA - Looking at difraction images">
   	<intro>
      	<description>
        	This Tutorial will show you how to get a first look at diffraction images to asses their general quality
    	</description>
   	</intro>
   	<item title="Open DIVA Perspective">
   		<command required="true"
   			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.diffractionviewerperspective)"/>
   		<description>	
   			The DIVA perspective is designed to make looking at diffraction images as easy as possible.
   		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open a Diffraction Image">
   	   	<description>
   			Use the File Navigator, go to the directory
   			<br/><br/><b>/dls/sci-scratch/ExampleData/ADSC-Q315/adsc</b>
   			<br/><br/>And then select the first image, you will see the Header information appear in the Header view just below the navigator.
        	<br/><br/>Now double click on the selected img file and you will see the image appear in the <b>Dataset Plot View</b> on the right hand side of the screen
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Navigating arround the image">
   	   	<description>	
   	   		Move the mouse over to the <b>Dataset Plot view</b> and experiment with the folowing tools which are available to allow you to look around the image.
   	   		<br/><br/><b>Middle mouse button, or both mouse buttons together</b>
			<br/>Pan around the image
			<br/><br/><b>Scroll Wheel</b>
			<br/>Zoom in and out of the image
			<br/><br/>Finaly to get information about where you are pointing at specifically activate the monitor which can be found in the row of buttons at the top of the <b>Dataset Plot View</b> it is the button that looks like a computer monitor and the tool-tip reads 'monitor the position in the image'
			<br/><br/>With this tured on, information can be found out about the image by moving the mouse pointer over it, this information is found at the bottom of the view.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Changing the colourscale on the image">
   	   	<description>	
			Sometimes to get the best out of the data, changing the way the pixel values are mapped to a specific colour can really help.
			<br/><br/>There is lots of functionality available here, but the easiest way to see a variety of different mappings is to use the Colour Scheme drop-down in the <b>Colour Mapping:Dataset Plot</b> and select a different colour scheme, Try a few different ones, but then end up on 'sqrt' which can be useful for pulling data out of the lower regions on the image.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Measure the d spacing between some spots">
   	   	<description>	
			To really investigate properties of the data collection, it is very useful to be able to measure the d-spacing of some of the reflections. 
			<br/><br/>To do this click on the Crystal icon at the top of the dataset plot, near the middle of the icons, and then bring the <b>side:Dataset Plot</b> to the front from behind the <b>Colour Mapping</b> view.  
			<br/><br/>In the <b>Side:Dataset Plot</b> view, select the Line Profile tab, which is to the far left of the tabs (you may need to use the arrows to move across to this tab)
			<br/><br/>In the main Dataset Plot navigate to an area with several spots in a row, and draw a line over 2 of them using the left mouse click.  When you do this a plot of the line profile should appear, with the peak positions marked on it.  Just below this is the d spacing statistics.
			<br/><br/>To improve the accuracy of this measurement, draw the line across several spots in a row, and you should see better statistics appear. 
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="resolution Rings">
   	   	<description>	
			To see resolution rings on the image, go to the second tab in the <b>Side:Dataset Plot</b> view, <b>Resolution Ring</b>.  This allows various markers to be set on the image, including standards and ice rings.
			<br/><br/>Check the toggle rings box to initialise this tool, and then click on Beam Centre button, which will show a point on the image which is where the metadata puts the beam centre.
			<br/><br/>Now click on Standard to get a set of resolution rings, the values of which are displayed in the table below. 
        </description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet> 
