<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Dataset Inspector Introduction">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This tutorial will show you how to use the dataset inspector.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Introduction">
		<description>
			The <b>Dataset Inspector</b> view comprises three parts. It divides its pane vertically
			and further divides the top part horizontally: the top parts are a <b>Data axes
			selection</b> table and a <b>Inspection tab folder</b> containing a number of examination
			options; and the bottom part holds a set of <b>Dataset slicing</b> user interface
			elements.
			<br/><br/>
			Begin reading the text above the axes selection table. This shows the inspected dataset
			that you selected earlier in the editor area. In some cases, a default dataset is
			automatically selected for your convenience. The text shows the name, the number of
			dimensions (or rank) and the dimension lengths of the chosen dataset.
			<br/><br/>
			Dataset Inspector is designed to cope with multi-dimensional datasets which are held
			hyper-rectangular arrays. Typically, these datasets are reduced in rank before any
			inspection. This is done by selecting a subset which is specified by <b>slicing</b>
			the dataset. With a 1-D dataset, a slice needs a start position, a stop position and a
			step size - the positions are the index values in the (linear) array that represent the
			dataset. Similarly, with a N-D dataset, the positions are sets of N index values and
			the step is the strides taken in each dimension.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Data axes selection">
		<description>
			Each dimension in the inspected dataset can be mapped to an axis dataset so that
			plotting along that dimension has abscissae given by that dataset. There is always a
			index dataset for each dimension that runs from 0 to L-1 where L is the length of the
			dimension and it is named "dim:x" where x is the dimension number.
			<br/><br/>
			Some file formats stored a number of datasets which can be used as axis datasets. In
			more complex scenarios, those datasets can be multi-dimensional too. In this case,
			appropriate slices of those datasets are taken to use as axis datasets and this is
			indicated by the suffix of ":x" where x is the dimension number of the axis dataset
			from which slice is taken.
			<br/><br/>
			Each row in the axes selection table shows those axis datasets available for that
			dimension and allows a choice to be made of which to use further on. 
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Dataset slicing">
		<description>
			An alternative way to specify a slice is to use the number of steps taken in each
			dimension instead of a stop position. The <b>Dataset slicing</b> part uses this way of
			selecting a slice. The part has a header row that labels the user interface elements
			and N rows of elements. These elements are the name of the axis dataset mapped to the
			dimension, a slider bar to show the extent of the slice and move the start position,
			the start value derived from the start position and the axis dataset, the number of
			steps in the slice, the step size and a reset button.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Inspection tab folder">
		<description>
			The <b>Inspection tab folder</b> contains many visualization and examination options
			that allow you to inspect the dataset.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>1D plot</b>
			<br/>
			This is a single line plotter. The line is plotted in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has a combo-box to allow you to choose which dimension, as referenced by
			the axis dataset name, to use for the x-axis.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>1D stack plot</b>
			<br/>
			This is a multiple lines plotter. The lines are plotted with different colours in
			the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane. The tab has two combo-boxes to allow you to choose
			which dimensions, as referenced by the axis dataset names, to use for x and
			z axes. The z-axis comes into play when the <b>In 3D</b> option is checked and also
			it specifies how the lines are selected. This is a maximum of 100 lines that can be
			plotted. The slicing is shows this fact by setting the number of steps in the
			dimension used as the z-axis to that limit.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D image</b>
			<br/>
			This is single image plotter. The image is shown in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has two combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions, as referenced
			by the axis dataset names, to use for x and y axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D surface</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 2D surface plotter. The surface is shown in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has two combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions, as referenced
			by the axis dataset names, to use for x and y axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D multiple images</b>
			<br/>
			This is a multiple images plotter. The images is shown in the <b>Dataset Plot</b>
			pane. The tab has three combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions, as
			referenced by the axis dataset names, to use for x, y and images axes. This is
			a maximum of 7 images that can be shown. The slicing is shows this fact by setting
			the number of steps in the dimension used as the images-axis to that limit.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D image explorer</b>
			<br/>
			This is a multiple images explorer. The images is shown in the <b>ImageExplorer
			View</b> pane. The tab has three combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions,
			as referenced by the axis dataset names, to use for x, y and images axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>3D volume</b>
			<br/>
			This is a volume renderer. The images is shown in the <b>Remote Volume View</b>
			pane. The tab has three combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions, as
			referenced by the axis dataset names, to use for x, y and z axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>1D scatter plot</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 1D points plotter. The points are plotted in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has two combo-boxes to allow you to choose whether the size of each point
			is constant or dependent on the dataset values and which dimension, as referenced
			by the axis dataset name, to use for the x-axis. The y coordinates of the points
			are determined by values of the inspected dataset.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D scatter plot</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 2D points plotter. The points are plotted in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has three combo-boxes to allow you to choose whether the size of each point
			is constant or dependent on the dataset value and which dimensions, as referenced
			by the axis dataset names, to use for x and y axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>3D scatter plot</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 3D points plotter. The points are plotted in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> pane.
			The tab has four combo-boxes to allow you to choose whether the size of each point
			is constant or dependent on the dataset value and which dimensions, as referenced
			by the axis dataset names, to use for x, y and z axes.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>1D data</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 1D table viewer. The values are shown in the <b>Dataset table</b> pane.
			The tab has a combo-box to allow you to choose which dimension, as referenced by
			the axis dataset name, to use for rows.
			<br/><br/>
			<b>2D data</b>
			<br/>
			This is a 2D table viewer. The values are shown in the <b>Dataset table</b> pane.
			The tab has two combo-boxes to allow you to choose which dimensions, as referenced by
			the axis dataset name, to use for columns and rows.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
