<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Looking at SRS files with Pilatus Images">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This Tutorial will show you how to view SRS files which contain Pilatus Images
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Open DEXplore Perspective">
		<command required="true"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.dataexplorationperspective)"/>
		<description>
			To visualise data effectively the DExplore Perspective is the best perspective to use,
			change to this now.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Create a new Project containing example data">
		<description>
			Create a new data project if you don't already have one from the Diamond Example Data.
			<br/><br/>
			To do this use File -> New -> Project, and then select Data -> Data Project and click
			on <b>Next</b>
			<br/><br/>
			Browse to the directory <b>/dls/sci-scratch/ExampleData</b> and click <b>OK</b>
			<br/><br/>
			The Data project should appear in the Project Explorer.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open A Pilatus Scan">
		<description>
			In the Example Data Project there is some Pilatus SRS data, navigate to its location
			which is:
			<br/><br/>
			<b>data -> SRS -> i16-SCAN -> pilatus</b>
			<br/><br/>
			In this directories are 2 files, single click or select the first of these
			'224668.dat' and you should see the <b>Header</b> view in the bottom right corner of
			the perspective fill with all the metadata from this file.
			<br/><br/>
			In the Header view there is a filter box at the top, into this empty box type <b>UB</b>
			and the list of all the metadata which has UB in the key will be shown, in this case it
			is the 9 elements of the UB matrix.
			<br/><br/>
			Now Double Click on the file <b>224668.dat</b> to open it for displaying the data.
			<br/><br/>
			The file should have now opened in the Editor area (previously blank) and show a list
			of all the datasets which are in this file, plus some information about them.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Plotting the Data From the File">
		<description>
			To plot some simple data from the file, simply click on the name of the data which you
			would like to see, in this case pick <b>roi3_maxval</b>. Once this is selected you
			should see the a double peaked plot appear in the Dataset Plot View.
			<br/><br/>
			This data is currently plotted against a default 'dim' axis, which is simply a count
			of the points in the plot, but it is often far more useful to plot the data against
			something else. To do this you simply need to select the axis in the <b>Data axes
			selection</b> part of the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> view, which is below the editor
			area. For this example select <b>Delta</b> as this was the scanned direction. You will
			see the x axis of the plot change to display in terms of delta.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Plotting the Pilatus Data">
		<description>
			At the bottom of the list of available data there is an element called <b>Pilatus</b>
			the Extra information about this is tagged as 'Not Available' due to the fact that this
			could be a lot of data, and we only load it off disk when it is needed, so values such
			as these cannot be calculated. Select this element now.
			<br/><br/>
			A new plot should have appeared, which is a little spiky, but the key thing which should
			be seen is that the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> is now reporting that the data it has
			access to is 3 dimensional. This means we can select to view the information in a
			variety of ways.
			<br/><br/>
			First lets look at the images which have been collected. to do this you need to change
			to the 2D image mode in the <b>Dataset Inspector</b>, this is done by selecting the
			<b>2D image tab</b> in the top right section of the view, you may need to expand the
			options if you cannot see it immediately by using the '>>' part to the right of
			existing tabs.
			<br/><br/>
			The Pilatus Image should now have appeared in the DataSet Plot. To change which Image
			is being viewed, you can use the dataset slicing section at the bottom of the <b>Dataset
			Inspector</b> view. Currently there is One Slicer bar which is not fully across and this
			is on Index at the top. Drag this bar about, and you will see the image change in the
			<b>Dataset Plot</b> view.
			<br/><br/>
			This is useful, but is made better if you once again select <b>delta</b> as the
			Dimension 1 axis in the Data axis selection part. Now the slider shows the value of
			delta corresponding to the image.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Advanced Slicing">
		<description>
			So far we have only done the simplest of slicing, and it is important to realise that
			there is much more functionality available. In this example we will see how a particular
			row of pixels changes with Delta.
			<br/><br/>
			To do this in the 2D image tab of the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> change the y-axis
			drop-down to 'delta'. This then shows a bit of a mess in the plotting window, but thats
			because we are looking at the top of every image, and the bit of interest to us is
			happening in the middle (where the peak appears).
			<br/><br/>
			To access this drag the 'dim:2' slider to towards the middle, and as you do you should
			see the data become apparent as a pair of lines.
			<br/><br/>
			There are also other ways of slicing, which can be explored, and the more you use it
			the more functionality becomes apparent. You should be aware though that slicing against
			the way the data was collected, as we have done here, can sometimes take a long time as
			the storage systems are not optimised to do this kind of thing.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Surface Plotting">
		<description>
			Finally lets look at one other way of plotting the data. Instead of '2D image' tab,
			select '2D Surface'
			<br/><br/>
			The same tools are available, just you are now viewing a surface plot, and not an image.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description>
			This tutorial has taken you through some basics of looking at SRS data which contains
			embedded Pilatus Data. But remember that the slicing and visualisation tools used here
			would work on any multidimensional dataset, and work especially well with NeXus files.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
