<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Looking at NeXus files">
   	<intro>
      	<description>
        	This Tutorial will show you how to view NeXus files
    	</description>
   	</intro>
   	<item title="Open DEXplore Perspective">
   		<command required="true"
   			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=uk.ac.diamond.scisoft.dataexplorationperspective)"/>
   		<description>	
   			To visualise data effectively the DExplore Perspective is the best perspective to use, change to this now.
   		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Create a new Project containing example data">
   	   	<description>
   			Create a new data project if you don't already have one from the Diamond Example Data.
   			<br/><br/>To do this use File -> New -> Project, and then select Data -> Data Project and click on <b>Next</b>
   			<br/><br/>Browse to the Directory <b>/dls/sci-scratch/ExampleData</b> and click <b>OK</b>
        	<br/><br/>The Data project should appear in the Project Explorer.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open a Nexus Scan">
   	   	<description>	
			In the Example Data Project there is some NeXus data, navigate to its location which is:
			<br/><br/><b>data -> NeXus</b>
			<br/><br/>Now Double Click on the file <b>2495.nxs</b> to open it for displaying the data.
			<br/><br/>The file should have now opened in the Editor area (previously blank) and show a list of all the file metadata and an entry dataset.
			<br/><br/>The file can be browsed through the NeXus Editor (Editor view) by clicking on the down-arrow left of <b>entry1</b> (unfolding the NeXus sub elements). It can also be browsed through the Project Explorer by unfolding the NeXus file itself.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Plotting the Data From the File">
   	   	<description>	
			To plot some simple data from the file, simply double click on the name of the data which you would like to see, in this case pick <b>EDXD_Element_03</b>, one of the sub element of <b>entry1</b>.
			<br/><br/>Alternatively, you can single click on that same data from the unfolded file in the <b>Project Explorer</b>. Once this is selected you should see the a single peaked plot with two discontinuities appear in the <b>Dataset Plot View</b>.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Multi dimensional data plotting">
   	   	<description>	
			The <b>Dataset Inspector</b> (Data axes selection part) is reporting that the data it has access to is 3 dimensional. This means we can select to view the information in a variety of ways.
			<br/><br/>First let's look at the images which have been collected. To do this you need to change to the 2D image mode in the <b>Dataset Inspector</b>; this is done by selecting the <b>2D image tab</b> in the top right section of the view, you may need to expand the options if you cannot see it immediately by using the '>>' part to the right of existing tabs.
			<br/><br/>The NeXus image should now have appeared in the DataSet Plot. To change which Image is being viewed, you can use the dataset slicing section at the bottom of the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> view. There is one slider bar which is not fully across, with 'edxd_q' next to it. Drag this bar about, and you will see the image change in the <b>Dataset Plot</b> view.
        </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Surface Plotting">
   	   	<description>	
			Lets look at one other way of plotting the data. Instead of '2D image' tab, select '2D Surface'
			<br/><br/>The same tools are available, just you are now viewing a surface plot, and not an image.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Stack Plotting">
   	   	<description>	
			Finally lets look at one other way of plotting the data. Select '1D Stack Plot'. This displays all the data plots 'stacked' together. 
			<br/><br/>With <b>edxd_q</b> as a x-axis and <b>dim:2</b> as a z-axis, pick the zoom tool (zoom button on Dataset Plot) and zoom on region of interests (the irregularities on the peak of the plot).
			<br/><br/>In the <b>Dataset Inspector</b> drag the <b>dim:1</b> slider to see the plot stack change.
			<br/><br/>Set the <b>z-axis</b> to <b>dim:1</b> and drag the <b>dim:2</b> slider to see the plot stack change.
			<br/><br/>Check the <b>in 3D</b> mode of the 1D Stack Plot to have a 3D view of your stacked plots. 
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
   	   	<description>	
			This tutorial has taken you through some basics of looking at an example NeXus data file. As a reminder, the slicing and visualisation tools used here would work on any multidimensional dataset (NeXus files being such possible datasets).	
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
